Well, this is the most exciting part of our Learning to program journey.
You've been through all sorts of things already.
You've been learning all the basics of programming in Python, and now we're going to take all of those
things, wrap them together and have some fun.
So in this section, what we're going to do is we're going to show you a game, a game that has been
written using turtle graphics.
You can see the game here on the screen.
And at first glance it looks like it's relatively complex.
It's actually not that complex at all.
As we quickly work through it, you will see that you understand most of what is here.
Just to give you a little taste of what you're going to be in for.
Let's run the game and just show you what you are going to be creating.
So it's just a little soccer game.
In the spirit of all these exciting adventures that are happening all the time around the world, things
like Soccer World Cups, or if you just play soccer, this is an exciting game to show you soccer.
Okay, so it's not a soccer game.
It's just getting you into the basics of it.
And basically it's kicking to score penalties.
So it's drawn our field.
And there we've got our little turtle who is a goalie.
And the turtle has to save the balls that are shot to the goals.
And there you see.
Well done.
There's a save by the turtle.
And each time a new ball is sent out in a random direction and the turtle missed that one.
So that is a goal.
So basically the aim of the game is to save the balls that are shot in random direction towards the
goal, and make sure you get there in time to save it.
So there it is.
Very exciting, relatively simple game, but lots of fun to make.
And obviously once we've worked you through all the details, you can fiddle and extend it and do so
many more things.
So let's get going and see how our Turtle Soccer World Cup game comes to be.